Speaker 1: -
Speaker 2: History of the Democrat
Party. I
Speaker 2: can say that his book saved me and it changed my life. So without further ado, you guys, please welcome to the stage, Dinesh D'Souza.
Speaker 3: -
Speaker 3: I need my own after hand.
Speaker 4: Not a yes sir, not a follow up. Not the box, not the mold. I see what I feel, yeah.
Take a
Speaker 5: look. - Thank you. Wow.
This is absolutely
Speaker 6: awesome. I'm thrilled to be here with Candice and be part of this important movement.
I was
Speaker 7: 17 years old when I first saw America. I remember the airplane descending on New York City. I looked out of the window. I saw the skyline. I saw the Statue of Liberty. And a very strange feeling came over me. I realized my life was going to be completely different from that moment on.
I
Speaker 7: felt I was moving from the margin of the world to the center, and I recognized in a very youthful way that I was coming to a country where I could be the architect of my own destiny. This is, to me, the great promise of the American dream. Notice,
by the
Speaker 7: way, that no other country really has a dream. I mean, the Chinese don't really have
a dream.
Speaker 7: There's no Indian dream. There may be a French dream, but I really don't want to know.
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): But when people talk about the American dream and they talk about immigrants, they think in terms just of economic opportunity, of American prosperity. And that is, in fact,
Speaker 7: part of the story. I have an acquaintance in Mumbai, in Bombay, India, who's been trying to come to America for many years.
Speaker 7: He's never
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): managed to get a visa. Finally, I said to the guy, I said, "Hey, why are you so eager to come to America?" He goes, "Dinesh,
I
Speaker 9: really want to move to a country where the poor people are fat."
Speaker 10: And
that
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): is, like I say, that is part of the story. I lived with a host family in Arizona.
And
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): they would say to me, "Dinesh, you're in a great state, Arizona. We want to take you sightseeing. We want to take you to see the Grand Canyon. We want to take you to see Tombstone, Arizona. You can see the fight at the O.K. Corral." And I was like, "Actually, if you want to take me sightseeing, take me to a grocery store. I want to see 17 types of cheese, 35 types of ice cream."
But,
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): bigger than that, I think what America has meant to me has been the chance to write the script of
Speaker 7: my own life. And that dream we embrace by becoming Americans, by embracing the principles of America.
The great
Speaker 7: obstacle to the American dream, for immigrants, for minorities, for blacks, for Latinos, for Asian Americans, has simply been the Democratic Party.
Speaker 6: That's the historical truth. But it's a truth that is beautifully hidden from the American people, and
Speaker 11: particularly from minorities. The reason for this is
Speaker 7: that the left has been so powerful in academia, in the media, and in Hollywood. And by Hollywood, of course, I mean the whole entertainment industry, the music industry, the comedians, Broadway,
And so
Speaker 11: when you control the megaphones of the culture, you control the narrative. The Democrats have been so successful in
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): controlling the narrative that they're able to convince Republicans that the Republicans are the bad guys. There was a head of the RNC, Ken Melman, a few years ago who was going to black churches and going to the NAACP and apologizing for the racist history of the Republican Party.
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): even
Speaker 12: though the Republican Party has no racist history.
Not only was the Democratic
Speaker 13: Party the party of
slavery, but
Speaker 13: it was also the party of segregation, of Jim Crow, of racial terrorism,
Speaker 7: of the Ku Klux Klan. In my last movie,
Speaker 7: "Death of a Nation", there's a scene
in
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): the movie where if you didn't know my work would be totally baffling. You see a scene in 1935 where all the heads of the major departments of the Nazis, the Justice Department and so on, are meeting in
a room
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): and in this room they are enacting
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): the Nuremberg Laws, which were the infamous laws making Jews into second-class citizens. And the Nazis are very
Speaker 11: proud of themselves. They believe they are creating, in their own words, the world's first racist state, which to them is an accomplishment.
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): They have a stenographer present to record the proceedings.
And as
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): the meeting begins, one of the Nazis puts his hand up and basically says to his fellow Nazis, we cannot create the world's first racist state because the Democratic Party has already done this in the United States. And
the Nazis look at each
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): other and they're embarrassed and quite frankly, they're a little pissed. They're
a little
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): pissed at being beaten to the punch. And
so they ask
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): this guy, well, what do you mean?
And he
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): says, well, what are we trying to do to the Jews? First, we're trying to segregate the Jews into ghettos. The Democrats have already passed segregation laws throughout the American South. Second, we want to outlaw miscegenation intermarriage between Jews and other Germans. The Democrats have already passed anti-miscegenation laws in 19 states.
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): And third, we want to confiscate the property of Jews, state-sponsored discrimination. He goes, "That is also the legacy of the Democratic Party in America." And so the Nazis adjourned the meeting, and they demand copies of these democratic laws. And when they get them and they reassemble, basically what they do is they take the democratic laws, cross out the word "black," write in the word "Jew,"
And
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): that is what we know today as the Nuremberg Laws. In other words, the Nuremberg Laws weren't just parallel
to the
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): racist laws of the Democratic Party, they were actually lifted directly from those laws. Now, interestingly, when I keep using the phrase the Democratic Laws, it seems a little odd, but the Nazis actually know something that is not taught in any high school or college in the United States, namely,
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): That every single segregation law in the American South from the 1880s to the 1950s was passed by a Democratic legislature, was signed by a Democratic governor, was enacted by Democratic officials, and there is no exception to this rule. Moreover...
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): The fact that the Nazis got their racist legislation from the United States, and specifically from the Democratic Party, this fact, to my knowledge, appears in no textbook, in no article. It's never been on the History Channel. It's never been on NPR. It's not in Wikipedia. It is simply a fact erased from history,
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): Even though it's indisputable, the meeting occurred, I have the transcripts, it's supported by
Speaker 11: scholarship, it happened, but it's been essentially whited out. Whited out. Now,
the left knows that
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): this is their history, and so in order to get out of it, their only way to get out
of it,
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): and this is what they put all their cards on today,
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): is the idea of the big switch. Which is the idea that the two parties switch sides. Exchange platforms. Now frankly, on the face of it, this is a little implausible. I mean, it's kind of like if someone wanted to tell you, hey guys, you know, in the 1970s, the cops all decided to become criminals.
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): and the criminals all decided to become cops. They just decided to switch sides. You'd be like, "Wow, how would that happen? "That sounds insane." But nevertheless, this idea of the big switch is argued with complete conviction and sincerity, and it is taught in our schools, and so the case really hangs on this. And it also hangs on the idea that, say, for example, the Republican Party today has nothing
to do
with
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): the legacy of Abraham Lincoln, that Lincoln, if he had lived today, would be a left-winger and a progressive. So I want to start by testing that idea. Very interestingly, when Lincoln defined slavery, Lincoln defined it not in racial terms. Lincoln said that the essence of slavery is captured in a simple idea. You work, I eat. In other words, the essence of slavery is theft. One guy does all the work, and the other guy steals the fruit of his labor.
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): Lincoln said that this is
Speaker 11: actually what the Democratic Party stands for both in the North and in the
South.
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): The idea of theft. And then Lincoln was asked what about the Republican Party? What does the Republican Party stand
Speaker 11: for? And Lincoln put it in his very homespun way. He goes, "The hand that makes the corn has the right to put the corn into its own mouth." In other words, we have the right
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): to
keep
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): the fruits of our labor and this is now this is Lincoln's position in the middle of the 19th century and yet I would say today if you fast-forward more than 150 years and you ask what is the credo of the Republican Party
what is
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): what is Trump stand for today I would argue the Trump basically stands for the fact that the hand that makes the corn has the right to put the corn in its own mouth no
change
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): And the Democratic Party has evolved in various ways. I would say the Democratic plantation today very different than it was in the 1830s and 40s. But nevertheless, if you were to sum up the core principle of the Democratic Party, is it not accurate to say that it's still today summed up by that simple Lincolnian description, you work and I eat.
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): One guy works and makes stuff, and another guy, or through the agency of the government, confiscates that stuff and disposes of
Speaker 11: it as they see fit. They still stand for the same thing, only in a different form. Now, what about this notion of the big switch? I'm going to zoom into this for just a moment because it's actually very important.
What
Speaker 11: really happened in America is that racism began to decline dramatically after World War II. The reason for this is kind of obvious. Hitler had built his whole ideology on racial supremacy. And so when American troops went into the gas chambers, they went into the concentration camps, they pulled out those starving, emaciated figures, basically racial supremacy took a mortal blow. And this fact,
which
Speaker 11: started in the
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): '40s and continued through the '50s, began to have a huge impact in America. And so, for example, Lyndon Johnson. Lyndon Johnson realized early on that the Democratic Party in the South had been built on the glue of white supremacy. That's what held the Democratic Party together. And if white racism was declining in the South, what was the future of the Democratic Party?
Speaker 14: there needed to be a new approach. Barry Goldwater, in 1964, opposed the Civil Rights Act of 1964. Now, interestingly enough, Goldwater was not a racist. In fact, he was the co-founder of the
Speaker 11: Arizona NAACP. He had been involved in the desegregation of the Phoenix schools. But Barry Goldwater was a libertarian, small
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): government, limited government.
And
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): when the Civil Rights Act of 1964 proposed the outlawing of discrimination, not just by the government, but also in the private sector, Goldwater opposed that on libertarian grounds. So he voted against the Civil Rights Act of 1964, and as a result, he won a handful of deep south states. But he lost the rest of the country. He won his home state of
Speaker 14: Arizona, and that was just about it. Lyndon Johnson swept the '64 election.
So when
Speaker 14: Richard Nixon
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): came along in 68, Richard Nixon learned from Goldwater's experience. Richard Nixon said, no, I'm not going to campaign for the votes of the Deep South. I'm actually going to campaign for the Sun Belt. And the Sun Belt was the...
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): the face of the changing South. The South was becoming less agricultural, more industrial. Northerners were moving south. There was tremendous growth in southern cities stretching all the way from St. Petersburg in Florida through Tampa, Raleigh, Dallas, Houston, all the way to Nixon's home state of California. That was the Sun Belt. So Nixon said, "I'm gonna go after the non-racist vote "of the urban South."
and
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): I'll do it by appealing to free markets, anti-communism, patriotism, family values,
Speaker 11: essentially the early phase of the Reagan agenda that emerged later in the 1980s. And Nixon won, not the Deep South, which went to George
Speaker 15: Wallace, the Democratic segregationist. Nixon won the so-called upper or peripheral South.
I tell you
Speaker 15: all this because all this history is
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): now distorted.
From
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): the point of view of the left, Nixon was a tricky dick. He made a sort of subtle appeal to deep south racists to come over to the Republican Party. So when people say this to me, I say to them, I challenge you to cite a single racist campaign statement made in public by Richard Nixon. Let's hear it. If
Speaker 11: Nixon is campaigning to the deep south racists, surely he said racist things. Where are
they?
Speaker 11: Nowhere. No one's ever been able to give an example. And so what they say is that no, Nixon didn't say any racist things, but he used
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): racist dog whistles.
And the
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): idea of the racist dog whistle, let's think about it for a minute, the idea of a dog whistle is that Nixon was making dog noises that nobody in the country could hear.
They
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): were at such a high pitch that the whole media, the whole country couldn't even hear them, but the racists who are the dogs have the heightened antenna that they alone could translate these messages and pick them up. I mean, this is the nonsense that is now masquerading for actual scholarship in the United States. The real proof of the pudding is simply to ask this question: If Nixon converted the racist Dixiecrats
Speaker 11: to be Republicans,
How
Speaker 11: many of them did he convert? And so in my last movie, Death of a Nation, I say,
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): all right, let's make a list of the Dixiecrats. Who are the Dixiecrats? They're the people who A, joined the Dixiecrat party, or B, voted against the Civil Rights Act of '64, or the Voting Rights Act of '65, or the Fair Housing Bill of '68. That is the definition of a Dixiecrat.
And
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): by that definition, there are about 150 Dixiecrats, congressmen, senators, governors, and so on the screen in the movie, boom, there they are. There are their names, there are all their photos. And now you ask, how many of those dudes became Republicans? And the correct answer is two.
One
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): in the House, Albert Watson, one in the Senate, Strom Thurmond, and every other racist Dixiecrat lived and stayed and died in the Democratic Party, have been lionized by Democrats. Their buildings in Washington, D.C. now are named after them, and this is the empirical fact. The beauty of living today is when I talk about this stuff on campus, students look at me like I'm from Mars, and I say, look, whip out your phone.
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): Type in racist Dixie Crap, look at all the names and now count to see how many of these guys switched.
So we
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): can today verify this information, which makes us very powerful. We
Speaker 11: can show that what we're saying is true and we can show that what they're saying is false.
There's a professor at Princeton
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): named Kevin Cruz.
Who
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): has actually assembled a sort of informal list of a hundred and fifty left-wing historians to refute me on these points and Their strategy is I would call it to emit a squid-like cloud of rhetoric to obfuscate the issue They're masters of obfuscation and so they'll say things like well, what about Jesse Helms? What about John Tower? My point is Jesse Helms and John Tower are not Dixiecrats
and
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): We're not asking whether any Democrats became Republicans. We're asking whether the specific faction of racist Dixiecrats became Republicans. Let's agree on our terms before we have an argument. Whenever I talk about slavery on campus, some professor of romance languages will jump up and go,
"Dinesh."
You're
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): pointing
Speaker 11: the finger at the Democratic party, but that's a lie. You know and I know that slavery is an American sin, Americans did it, and there's plenty of blame to go around. First of all, I make the obvious
Speaker 15: point that America doesn't do things, some Americans do them, and other Americans try to
stop them, right?
And then the way to
Speaker 16: crush the debate and to win it completely is what I
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): call the incendiary fact. And so here's my incendiary fact. In 1860, which is
Speaker 16: the year before the Civil War, no Republican owned a slave. Now notice I'm not saying that no Republican leader owned a slave. I'm
Speaker 11: saying that no Republican in the United States owned a slave.
And
Speaker 11: if that's true, if that's
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): true, it means that all the slaves in the country, there were four million at the time. This was the zenith of American slavery. Four million slaves were all owned
by Democrats. Now this
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): is the kind of statement that kind of reminds me, if you will, of an atheist who was reading through the Bible. He read it from the beginning to the end. And at the end, he made a small note in the margin. He wrote, important if true. Important if true.
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): That's applicable to my statement, important if true. But the beauty of my statement is it's, in a scientific sense, refutable. All you have to do is give me the name of one solitary Republican who owned a slave,
and I
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): would have to take it back. And yet to this day, two and a half years after I made this assertion for the first time, and despite innumerable and tireless effort, media matters, you can only imagine all these people doing their very best to ferret out a single counter example,
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): have not been able to do it about six months ago a fellow at the university of michigan wrote me and he goes dinesh i gotcha i gotcha ulysses s grant inherited a slave a single slave but nevertheless a slave on his wife's side and i said man that is what i called an almost touche you almost had me but i gotta point out to you that at the time this happened ulysses s grant was
a democrat
He became a
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): Republican later. Now,
why is all
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): this important? It's important because fake news sits on top of fake history. Fake narratives about America. Attempts to con us and intimidate us and put us up against the wall. Part of our liberation
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): It's not just the ability to read between the lines, to figure out when you're being conned,
but also to
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): be able to deconstruct these fake narratives. And so as you arm yourself and equip yourself with knowledge, you become what
Speaker 14: I call a very dangerous American. You'll notice that the other side is a little bit, whenever you start speaking,
Speaker 11: they get extremely nervous
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): and agitated because they know that everything they're going to say, you already know. But what you're going to say, they have no idea.
and
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): they have no comeback. So they're completely disarmed. It's actually a kind of an exciting notion because it makes you a powerful figure in the
Speaker 14: American debate. It arms you with truth and with knowledge, and you're the one who actually knows what you're talking about.
Martin
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): Luther King has a beautiful line which has always inspired me. It's actually not the line about the content of our character.
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): He says, "Ultimately, every man must write
Speaker 14: with his own hand "the charter of his Emancipation Proclamation."
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): And I think what he means by this is that in a society of equal rights under the law, we have the right to be treated equally by the government. We have that
right. But
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): we don't have any more rights than this. And what we do with our freedom and what we make of our liberty and what we make of our lives, this ultimately is up
to us.
I was,
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): as part of my penance with the Obama administration, I was sentenced to teach immigrants,
mainly Latino,
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): about the English language. And one time, one of my students asked me an interesting question. She said, you're all involved in American politics and we don't understand any of it.
what
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): really is the main difference between the two parties? How would you summarize it? What's the core of it? And I realized, I felt a little helpless for a moment 'cause I realized that my normal way of talking, appealing, say, to the American founding or the Constitution, all of that was remote from these people. These are people whose big challenges were things like, how do I buy a ticket to go get on the bus, to go to get to Target where I can work?
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): So, these are people who are operating at the most basic level and they want me to explain American politics at that level. And so I want to leave you with my thought about how
I think
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): American politics can be divided at the simplest level. I think, essentially, there are two models for people who start at the bottom to move to the top or to improve their
Speaker 15: life. The first is the model of
the ladder
Speaker 15: and the second is the model
of the rope. So
Speaker 15: the ladder is the ladder of opportunity.
And
Speaker 15: that's what the Republican Party stands for. Ladders of opportunity. Now the government does
have a role
Speaker 15: to hold the ladder, which means
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): to protect our rights. Some of us are gonna get higher or lower on the ladder depending on how we climb, and also depending on factors we don't control, like luck. But nevertheless, the ladder represents, for the most part, earned achievement. And when you get up on the ladder, you can say, this is my life, I made it, I did
it.
The
Speaker 11: other approach,
Speaker 15: which is a democratic approach, is the rope. And you can think of the rope as a bunch of guys, these are the Democrats, they're on the top of a building, and we lowly minorities and immigrants are all down there, and they let down the rope. And they go, okay guys, hang on to the rope, we're gonna pull
you up.
Speaker 15: That's their model. Now, on the first glance, the ladder is less appealing
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): than the rope. Why? Because the ladder you actually have
to climb.
The rope
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): you're just supposed to hold on. It seems easier.
But if
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): you think about it, it soon dawns on you that you're very dependent on the guys who hold the
rope
Speaker 15: on the other end. If they let go, down you go.
And so a
Speaker 15: second point is if you stick
around a
Speaker 15: little while and kind of watch the rope in action, you begin to realize that a lot of people who take the rope
Speaker 15: never seem to get to the top. You notice
Speaker 16: they get to the middle or they get off the ground and then the people on top of the building seem to hold. They don't pull, they hold. And then it occurs to you that maybe those people don't want any of these guys to get to the top.
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): Why? Because they've got you where they want you. You're in a position of suspended dependency. You're too far from the ground to drop
and
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): you're not far enough from the top to be able to climb on your own, you just hang there. And so, I think that for all of us, ultimately, we're faced with
Speaker 15: this simple choice. Do we want an America of the ladder, or do we want an America of the rope? In the America of the
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): rope, you have this guardian class that seems to get all the benefits that needs us
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): because they offer us crumbs in exchange for the thing that they want most
from us.
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): Not today, we're not in the days of slavery. They don't want to steal our labor. In fact, they want something from us that they think is free for us to give, our vote.
And
Speaker 16: so they need us to vote for them to keep the whole rope mechanism going.
But it seems to
Speaker 14: me that our liberation is to recognize that that's actually not the
way.
We
Speaker 14: don't want our destiny to be dependent on them. We want our destiny to be dependent on us. The way forward is the way of the ladder. That is our future. That's how we begin to achieve the same dream that so many earlier generations have enjoyed.
Speaker 14: That's how we move America for all Americans closer to what Reagan meant when he spoke so beautifully now a few decades ago of what he called mourning in America. Thank you very much. Thank you.